Pedram Khoshnevis

Email: Pedramkhoshnevis@gmail.com

Tell: +1-306-580-3888

Portfolio: http://www.webprinciples.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/pedramkhoshnevis

GitHub: https://github.com/pedramvdl31

SUMMARY

I have 5 years of professional programming experience and during this time, I have developed countless programs to solve any challenging problems that I have faced. I am detail oriented, a quick learner and a team player. In regards to programs developed, I pay special attention to ensure that security, integrity, and efficiencies are maintained. My previous work experience has given me knowledge of the proper object-oriented programming practices and the proper usage of synchronous and asynchronous functions. I have experience working with SQL, NoSQL databases, scripting languages, following the Application Programming Interface (API) manuals. My studies in Computer Science with a Minor in Management has familiarized me with Customer Relationship Management (CRM), Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP), Project Management, and Business Analysis. I have an excellent working knowledge of all aspects of computers and Information Technology (IT). This includes software, hardware, networking, distributed systems, and desktop support.

EDUCATION

University of Seoul
 Mar 2013 – Mar 2015

Master of Computer Science, Computer Networking.

Honors in General Scholarship. GPA 95%.

Publication: An Adaptive Network Coding scheme for unreliable multi-hop wireless networks.

University Science Malaysia

Mar 2007 - Mar 2011

Jan 2014 - Present

Bachelor of Computer Science, Distributed Systems and Network Security.

Minor: Management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **Development:** JavaScript, PHP(Laravel), React-Native, Node.js, MongoDB, Redis, Socket.io, Git, Rest-Full API design, C++, Python.
- Frontend Development: HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, PhoneGap / Cordova, Ionic, Angular.js.
- Database Management: MySQL (Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, and Durability), NoSQL MongoDB, Database ORM, Database Migration and Seeding.
- Platform Tools: AWS, EC2, Route 53, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, Elasticsearch.
- **Security:** Public and Private key (SSL), Password Protection (Hash, Salt, Pepper), Security (CSRF Tokens; Cookie Encryption and Decryption, Sessions).

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

University of Regina (IT researcher) – Regina, Canada Apr 2018 – Sept 2018

Apposha.io (Senior Web Developer) – Seoul, South Korea Jul 2017 – Apr 2018

Ubutoday.com (IT Director) – Remote Based

FantaPlan (Web Developer) – Seoul, South Korea Apr 2015 – Apr 2016

rantarian (Web Developer) – Seoul, South Korea Apr 2015 – Apr 2016

WebPrinciple (Freelance Web Developer and Designer)

Jan 2015 – Present

Eyelevate (Web Developer) – Seoul, South Korea Feb 2014 – Jan 2015

- Eyelevate: Developed responsive web applications using the MVC framework Laravel (PHP). Applications were integrated with many APIs and Git was used as the version-control software. Applications server side was developed using Linux, Apache2, MySQL, and PHP (LAMP Stack), and the client side completed using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript. During my work at Eyelevate I was officially recognized for providing excellent customer service to our clients.
- **Freelance Web Developer and Designer:** Coordinated and communicated with customers to plan web development projects from concept through completion, utilizing a variety of web development tools and technology.
 - Created complex graphics and professional designs for a variety of businesses, organizations, professionals, and individuals, including custom graphic and logo design.
 - Provided web solutions and developed websites and web applications based on specific business needs for promotions, presentations, customer service, and online services.
 - Managed, maintained and updated existing websites for customers and provided customer service.
 - Ensured all web site development followed W3C web standards and ADA compliance for accessibility and other good practices for web design and development.
- **Ubutoday.com:** I am in charge of all IT related tasks including website development and maintenance. As a group, we acquired a Federal grant to help numerous clients access our services. UBU Today is a non-profit organization that provides education, resources, workshops and access to world-renowned natural techniques as a springboard for renewed personal growth, hope and healing.
- FantaPlan and Apposha: I developed an application similar to Amazon Web Services (AWS) to provide a database as a service tool. I developed a Content Management System (CMS) to accommodate such tools. The application was a multi-user platform which familiarized me with server problems such as double spending and databases Atomicity and Consistency properties. Working at Apposha also gave me experience in using AWS tools such as Elastic Beanstalk, Elasticsearch, CloudFormation, and Route53. Throughout my work, we acquired multiple government startup support and venture capital investments.
- University of Regina (IT researcher): Providing programming support to the biology lab. Mainly working with computer vision algorithms using C and C++ to create and work with Structure from Motion (SFM) algorithm. Working at the University of Regina has familiarized me with Canadian work culture and ethics.

References Available Upon Request